[音乐]
[Music]
所以我是吉尔伯特斯特朗，这是关于
so I'm Gilbert Strang and this is about
我的新课程18065和新的
my new course 1806 5 and the new
教科书线性代数和学习
textbook linear algebra and learning
从数据和这些主题中的内容
from data and what's in those subjects
所以他们真的是两个必不可少的主题
so they're really two essential topics
和两个补充，但所有这些
and two supplementary but all of them
非常重要的科目，如果我告诉你
very important subjects so if I tell you
关于数学的这四个部分
about those four parts of mathematics
这是在给你的过程中
that are in the course that'll give you
一个想法，如果你有兴趣关注
an idea if you're interested to follow
通过这样的第一个主题是
through so the first big subject is
线性代数这一问题刚
linear algebra that subject has just
飙升的重要性在
surged exploded in importance in
练习我想要关注的是一些
practice what I want to focus on is some
最好的矩阵说对称
of the best matrices say symmetric
矩阵正交矩阵及其矩阵
matrices orthogonal matrices and their
关系那些是星星
relation those are those are the stars
线性代数和关键步骤是
of linear algebra and the key step is to
因子矩阵可以是对称的
factor a matrix into may be symmetric
时间正交矩阵可以是
times orthogonal matrix may be
正交时间对角线时间
orthogonal times diagonal times
正交矩阵非常
orthogonal matrix that's a very
重要的分解称为
important factorization called the
奇异值分解是
singular value decomposition that
没有进入很多线性代数
doesn't get into a lot of linear algebra
课程，但它是如此重要，所以我可以
courses but it's so critical so can I
现在谈谈第二个重要的事情
speak now about the second important
话题是深度学习有啥
topic which is deep learning so what is
深入学习它的工作就是创造
deep learning it's the job is to create
创建一个您输入的功能
a create a function you have your inputs
就像无人驾驶汽车的输入一样
are like for driverless cars the input
将是一个电话的图像
would be an image that's a telephone
杆或行人和系统
pole or a pedestrian and the system
学习识别它是什么或者是什么
to learn to recognize which it is or the
来自地址的手写输入
inputs from handwriting on on addresses
将是一个邮政编码，因此系统必须
would be a zip code so the system has to
学习如何识别0123到9
learn how to recognize 0 1 2 3 up to 9
从各种手写或其他
from handwriting of all kinds or another
一个是Siri必须做的演讲
one is speech like what Siri has to do
所以我的发言得到输入
so my speech has to get input and
通过过程解释和输出
interpreted and output by the process of
深度学习，所以它涉及创建一个
deep learning so it involves creating a
学习功能该功能需要
learning function the function takes the
输入数据并产生输出
input the data and produces the output
这些数据的含义以及如何
the meaning of that data and so how
什么是这样的功能
what's the function like that's what
数学是关于功能的
mathematics is about functions so it
涉及配偶它涉及矩阵
involves mate it involves matrix
乘法部分功能是
multiplications part of the function is
通过矩阵乘以向量
multiplying vectors by matrices so
这是一堆步骤，但如果有的话
that's a bunch of steps but if there was
只有它是所有线性代数
only that if it was all linear algebra
事情会失败并失败了
the thing would fail and has failed what
使它现在的工作非常公司
makes it work now so much that companies
正在投资巨大的Lea
are investing enormous Lea in the
技术是现在的
technology is that there's now a
非线性函数非常简单
nonlinear function a very simple one in
每对之间的中间
the middle between every pair of
矩阵，这不仅仅是我的功能
matrices and that not only function I
甚至可以告诉你它是什么
can even tell you what it is it's the
函数f让我们称之为X的ff
function f let's call it f f of X is
如果X是正数而f是X，则等于X.
equal to X if X is positive and f of X
如果X为负数，则为0，这样您就可以想象
is 0 if X is negative so you can imagine
它的图表是一条平坦的线条
its graph it's a flat line where it's
负面，然后它是一个45度的斜率
negative and then it's a 45-degree slope
把它放在哪里是积极的
where it's positive so putting that
矩阵之间的非线性函数
nonlinear function in between the matrix
乘法是构建的方式
multiplications is the way to construct
学习成功的学习功能但是
learn successful learning function but
你必须找到那些矩阵，所以我
you have to find those matrices so I
提到支持科目
mentioned to supporting subjects
首先是优化将是
the first is optimization would be the
我们必须找到这些条目
we have to find the entries in those
进入学习的矩阵
matrices that go into the learning
功能这是至关重要的一步
function that's a crucial step so this
是一个最小化错误的问题
is a problem of minimizing the error
所有这些矩阵条目为
with all those matrix entries as
变量因此这是多变量的
variables so this is multivariable
微积分就像十万五
calculus like a hundred thousand five
十万变量只是
hundred thousand variables is just
在基础微积分课程中是不可想象的但是
unthinkable in basic calculus course but
它发生在一家公司里面
it's happening in in a company that's
深学习工作，所以这是
working with deep learning and so that's
这是深刻的巨大计算
it that's the giant calculation of deep
了解这是GPU的发展方向
learning that's what keeps GPUs going
一个星期，但它给出了惊人的结果
for a week but it gives amazing results
这在以前是无法实现的
that could never have been achieved in
过去那么另一个关键主题
the past so then the other key subject
是统计和基本思路
is statistics and the basic ideas of
统计在这里起作用，因为何时
Statistics play a role here because when
你将整个序列相乘
you're multiplying a whole sequence of
深度学习的矩阵非常
matrices in deep learning it's very
这些数字可能会增长
possible for the numbers to grow out of
以指数方式或降至零
sight exponentially or to drop to zero
而这两个都是坏消息
and both of those are bad news for the
学习功能所以你需要保持
learning function so you need to keep
右边的平均值和方差
the mean and variance at the right spot
保持这些数字在学习中
to keep those numbers in the learning
将这些矩阵运用于良好的功能中
function those matrices in in a good
范围所以你这个课程不会是一个
range so it's you this course won't be a
统计课程，但它会使用
statistics course but it will use
深度学习这样的统计数据
statistics as deep learning does so
那些是线性的四个主题
those are the four subjects linear
代数和深度学习两大问题
algebra and deep learning two big ones
优化和统计必不可少
optimization and statistics essential
所以我希望你会喜欢这些视频
also so I hope you'll enjoy the videos
和
and
这需要两个，然后去
that takes both and go to the
OpenCourseWare网站ocw.mit.edu
OpenCourseWare site ocw.mit.edu
了解视频以外的全貌
for the full picture beyond the videos
有运动问题讨论
there are exercises problems discussion
更多的是使它成为一个完整的
lots more toward making it a complete
我希望你喜欢的演讲
presentation which I hope you like
您
you